Guide to the Noah C. Saxton Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Noah C. Saxton Papers
1816-1834
RG 123
Yale University Divinity School Library
0.5
(1 box)
Correspondence, diaries, and sermons document Saxton's evangelistic work. Noah C. Saxton (1798-ca. 1834) was an evangelist in Connecticut, New Jersey, and New York.
Saxton, Noah C.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from dealer.
Biographical / Historical
1798 Jan 24 Born, lived in Wilbraham, Massachusetts
1822 Conducted evangelistic ministry--largely in New Jersey, Westchester and Suffolk Counties, New York, and Greenwich area of Connecticut Licensed and ordained for work as an evangelist Studied for the ministry under Alfred Ely Attended Union College
ca. 1834 Died
Scope and Contents
These papers shed light on the training, life, and work of Noah C. Saxton, an early nineteenth century evangelist in America. A detailed summary of the collection prepared by Constance R. Spande is available in folder 17.
Arrangement
I. Diaries, 1827-1830
II. Correspondence, 1816-1834
III. Sermons, 1829, n.d.
IV. Biographical and Collected Material, 1819-1822, n.d.
Evangelistic work -- Connecticut; Evangelistic work -- New Jersey; Evangelistic work -- New York (State); Evangelists; Saxton, Noah C.
- Diaries, 1827-1830; Series I
  - Six volumes, 1827-1830 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1816-1834; Series II
  - Noah C. Saxton
    - From cousin, Experience, 1816 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - To father, Noah Saxton, 1817, 1819, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - From Eliza M. Babbitt, 1821 Nov 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - From Mary Shelton, 1821 Nov 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - To father, 1823, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - From James B. Taylor, 1825, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - To son, Francis Saxton, 1833 Aug 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mary Saxton (sister of Noah)
    - From cousin, Experience, 1816 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - From Emeline Cotton, 1819 Jul 18 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - To Sally Eliza Langdon, 1821, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - To nephew Francis Saxton, c. 1834 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sermons of Noah C. Saxton, 1829, n.d.; Series III
  - Psalm 17:15, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Proverbs 28:26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ezekiel 33:11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Matthew 6:33 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Matthew 23:23 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Luke 9:62 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Luke 11:21, 22 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Luke 16:25 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Luke 18:26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Acts 3:19 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Acts 8:21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Romans 8:8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - I Corinthians 7:29 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hebrews 12:16, 17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Biographical and Collected Material, 1819-1822, n.d.; Series IV
  - Certification of Noah Sexton, Jr. as member of Church of Christ in South Wilbraham, Massachusetts, 1819 Apr 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Copy of the minutes of the Council that set apart Noah G. Saxton for the work of an Evangelist", 1822 Nov 26 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Song: "Rejoice in thy Youth", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bill for goods, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notes of NCS, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - In handwriting of Mary Saxton (?): "Lecture on the Atonement by Dr. Alexander" (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - In handwriting of Mary Saxton (?): 2 religious statements (Box 1, Folder 16)